[Music]
[Applause]
the lion the mouse and the sleepy bear
once upon a time
in a lush forest there lived a small
mouse there was a huge bear who lived in
a neighboring cave the big bear who had
hibernated months ago
was still sleeping and snoring loudly
the little mouse went to him one day to
wake the bear up because he could not
sleep all winter
due to the bear's noisy snoring
mr bear
hey mr bear hey
summer has come you can wake up any time
now however the bear still did not wake
up the little mouse came to the bear
this time with a bugle he blew
vigorously into the bugle
but the bear continued to sleep
while the little mouse was wandering
sleeplessly in the forest he met several
animal friends what happened little
mouse why are you sad oh
don't ask guys all winter i could not
sleep because of the bears snoring and
he still won't wake up
hmm
maybe the lion can help you
what
why would i go talk to him
because the lion roars so loud that
everyone jumps up the instant i hear his
loud voice
though the little mouse was a little
scared by the thought
he went to the lion the king of the
forest to request his assistance the
lion was sleeping in front of his cave
the little mouse was terrified when he
saw the mighty beast so he decided to
give up his plan and go back home but
when he accidentally stepped on a branch
in front of him the big cat woke up and
a tiny trembling voice reached his ears
what's that noise what are you doing in
front of my cave
um
well the king of the forest
sorry to wake you up
well
i um
came to ask for your help you're not
even big enough to be considered snack
size little mouse why should i help you
dear fearsome lion you have to wake up
my neighbor the big bear who won't wake
up from hibernation
nothing i do seems to wake him since i'm
small i have a little voice
but one roar from you can solve
everything
i don't have time to spend for a tiny
little useless mouse like you i am king
of the forest
the lion walked away without helping the
mouse he went to a corner where no one
could see him he leaned against a tree
and started to itch like crazy
[Music]
the lion was so itchy that he didn't
want anyone to see him like this
because he was the king of the forest
the little mouse on the other hand was
coming home sadly and heard wheezing
from the depths of the forest
he went where the voice came from and he
saw the lion moreover the lion was
itching himself non-stop and looking
rather silly in the process the mouse
immediately approached the lion when the
lion saw him he stopped itching but it
was clear he was still in pain and
discomfort due to the itch mr lyon what
happened to you
i don't know mouse i don't know
i can't stop itching myself
you haven't seen or heard anything mouse
are we clear
the mouse carefully fixed his tiny eyes
on the lion and saw a bunch of tiny
fleas
jumping in his fur the mouse understood
why the mighty cat was itching so much
oh
you have fleas let me help you
how can you help me you're just a little
mouse
leave me alone
the little mouse bravely jumped on him
ignoring the lion's rude comments
[Music]
what are you doing
get off of me the mouse started to crawl
through the thick scruffy fur and throw
out all the fleas
but this made the lions situation even
worse
he started itching himself with his paws
the lion could not bear the itch and
leaned his back against the tree this
time he started to rub right and left oh
no
i was almost crushed
i can't stop i can't stop the more you
run over me the more i itch get off
sir
the lion ran to a nearby lake he quickly
jumped into the water
the mouse on his back was nearly drowned
mr lion get out of the water right away
or i'll drown
the lion came out of the lake but then
proceeded to shake himself dry he was
shaking his body so hard and so fast
that the mouse barely was able to hang
on to that thoughtless lion i've almost
got the edge taken care of mr lion
just a little bit more to the left
the lion
finally stopped himself
the mouse threw out the last few fleas
that remained on the lion
how do you feel now
well
it's like my itching is gone
because i have cleaned all the fleas for
you sir the lion was very embarrassed
with how rude he was
when you asked for help i looked down on
you mouse
but you still did everything in your
power to save me from this difficult
situation
thank you you're welcome mr lion come on
hop on my back and i'll take you home
when the little mouse and the big lion
arrived at the mouse's home they heard
loud snoring sounds flooding out of the
big bear's cave
huh what's that noise
they then
entered the cave
ah
you were right mouse
summer has come
the big bear is still sleeping the lion
the king of the forest took a deep
breath and roared so powerfully
right into the ears of the big bear
that the stone floor of his cave shook
thanks to this powerful roar the bear
finally woke up and ran out of the cave
[Music]
what happened is there something wrong
what happened did the sun come out
is it summer
where is it well all the forest animals
laughed at the big silly bear
little mouse was also very happy that
the snoring was finally over